PROFILE

Creative and self-motivated full stack developer with a drive for developing and maintaining business solutions. Experience with both onsite and contract positions, web and desktop application development. Excellent soft skills, including written and verbal communication, problems solving and time management.

CONTACT

94 Cemetery St.
Dickinson Center, NY 12930
(206) 849-4672
RyanScottGibbs@gmail.com

SKILLS

Languages/Libraries:

Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, MySQL, SQL, MongoDB, C#, ASP.NET, VBA

Applications:

Visual Studio, Git, Microsoft Office Suite, Access, Sage 50 Accounting, Misys ERP, vTiger CRM

Education

Henry Cogswell College Bachelor of Arts, Digital Arts

RYAN GIBBS

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Self Employed Contractor 2019 to Present

EZPolitix

- Frontend team lead and developer for CRM project.
- Organized and managed Gitlab ticketing system for both frontend and backend teams.
- Mapped existing database and reverse engineered data flows.

Fulgent Group

 Sole frontend web developer for internal document repository application for financial sector client.

Pro Refrigeration, Inc.

- Added features to existing internal configuration tool, expanding product capabilities and linking to external CRM system.
- Updated order entry application to link to current accounting software version.
- Refactored IOT customer interface to include new content.
- Offered troubleshooting services to client and refactored existing codebase to run as expected.

Pro Refrigeration, Inc. 2011 to 2019

Developer 2017 to 2019 Master Scheduler 2011 to 2017

- Maintained and expanded customer service order entry software entry portal to push data to all internal order management software and tools.
- Developed web-based item configuration tool for sales team that allowed simple and remote product mockup and quote generation.
- Created intranet portal that aggregated sales and production data and displayed reports to simplify the understanding of the datasets.
- Acted as development liaison with external team for IOT data collection hardware offered with company's product.